Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. And I'm Erika. And today
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。我是Marco。我是Erika。今天
we're bringing you a very, I would say, embarrassing lesson for us men. Right, embarrassing for
我们要给你们带来一堂，我觉得，对我们男人来说很尴尬的课。对，对男人尴尬
men but I think it's okay for women. That's right, we're going to be talking about buying
但我觉得对女人来说还行。没错，我们要讨论买
underwear, specifically women's underwear. Right, so obviously not the favorite thing
内衣，特别是女式内衣。对，所以显然这不是男人最喜欢做的事。
for men to do. Well, apart from being a little bit uncomfortable, it's also boring. Yeah,
嗯，除了有点不自在，还很无聊。是啊，
it involves shopping, right? It involves shopping, so we're not really big on that. Alright,
它涉及购物，对吧？涉及购物，所以我们不太喜欢。好了，
but well, even though it might be a little bit of an uncomfortable topic, there is some
但尽管这可能是个有点尴尬的话题，里面还是有一些
great language in here, isn't there? Yeah, there's some really good words and of course
很棒的语言，对吧？是啊，有一些非常好的词汇，当然
the different types of underwear that we're going to be looking at. But we also have some
还有我们要看的不同类型的内衣。但我们也有一些
words that we're going to take a look at before we get into our dialogue, so let's start with
在进入对话之前要看的词汇，所以我们从
vocabulary preview.
词汇预览开始。
Vocabulary preview. Well, we're going to look at two words that will appear in our dialogue.
词汇预览。嗯，我们要看两个会在对话中出现的词。
And the first one is lingerie. Okay, so lingerie, this is a nice fancy word, basically for underwear,
第一个是lingerie。好，lingerie，这是一个花哨的词，基本上就是内衣，
right? Right, for women's underwear. So lingerie, but it's very nice, very... Like pretty, sexy.
对吧？对，女式内衣。所以lingerie，但它是很漂亮的，很……像漂亮、性感。
Sexy underwear, yeah. Now, the spelling of this word is interesting, isn't it? Yeah,
性感内衣，是的。现在，这个词的拼写很有趣，对吧？是啊，
it's spelled L-I-N-G-E-R-I-E. Lingerie. Yes, don't you love English spellings? So women's
拼写是L-I-N-G-E-R-I-E。Lingerie。是的，你不喜欢英语的拼写吗？所以女式
nice pretty sexy underwear. That's right. And our second word, awkward. Awkward. Awkward.
漂亮性感的内衣。没错。我们的第二个词，awkward。Awkward。Awkward。
So this is a feeling that men have, especially when they're buying women's underwear. Well,
这是男人会有的一种感觉，特别是当他们买女式内衣的时候。嗯，
yeah, you feel a little bit uncomfortable or it's a strange situation. Or weird or out
是啊，你会觉得有点不自在，或者这是个奇怪的情况。或者怪异或格格不入。
of place. It's awkward. Yes. All right, so we're going to be hearing both of these two
很尴尬。是的。好了，我们会在对话中听到这两个词。
words in the dialogue. Now, Marco, where are we here? We're going to be at a department
现在，Marco，我们这是在哪儿？我们要去一家百货
store at the section where they have women's lingerie and we have a guy buying underwear
商店的女式内衣区，有一个男人在给他女朋友买内衣。
for his girlfriend. All right, well, let's find out what happens.
好了，我们来看看会发生什么。
This sucks. I hate buying lingerie. Okay, just find something and get out of here. All right,
真烦。我讨厌买内衣。好，随便找点东西然后离开这里。好了，
these are fine. Oh, no, don't come over here. Don't come over here. You look a little lost.
这些还行。哦，不，别过来。别过来。你看起来有点迷茫。
Can I help you? I'm just having a look around. It's my girlfriend's birthday tomorrow. I'm
需要帮忙吗？我只是随便看看。明天是我女朋友的生日。我
trying to find her something. Well, you can't give her granny panties. Have you thought
想给她找点东西。嗯，你不能给她买老奶奶内裤。你有没有想过
about getting her some sleepwear? We've got these lovely silky nighties or how about some
给她买点睡衣？我们有这些可爱的丝质睡裙，或者来点
nice panties and a bra set? Look, here's a nice satin push up bra and you can choose
漂亮的内裤和文胸套装怎么样？看，这是个不错的缎面聚拢文胸，你可以选
a few different styles of undies to go with it. Sure, that's fine. This is so awkward.
几种不同风格的内裤来搭配。好的，可以。这太尴尬了。
What else do I pick? What size is she? Well, do you want a thong? Some bikini briefs? Maybe
我还选什么？她穿什么尺码？嗯，你想要丁字裤吗？一些比基尼内裤？也许
this nice pair of lacy boy shorts. Just pick something and get the hell out of here. I'll
这条漂亮的蕾丝平角短裤。随便挑一个然后赶紧离开这里。我
go with these two. This is mortifying. I just want to get this over with and she better
就选这两个。这太丢人了。我只想赶紧结束这件事，她最好
thank me for this. Here you are, sir. I'm sure she'll enjoy them. Finally. I'm sorry,
感谢我。给您，先生。我相信她会喜欢的。终于好了。对不起，
sir. I'm going to have to take a look inside your bag. Oh, the poor guy. I totally feel
先生。我得检查一下你的包。哦，可怜的家伙。我完全
bad for him. Yeah, he was really nervous and of course it was very uncomfortable for him.
为他感到难过。是啊，他真的很紧张，当然对他来说也很不自在。
I know and then the security guard shows up. Exactly. But we had the opportunity to take
我知道，然后保安出现了。没错。但我们有机会
a look at some really great words and phrases. So let's start off with our first one in language
看到了一些很棒的词汇和短语。所以我们从语言要点开始。
takeaway. Language takeaway. All right, well we're going to look at words here that mostly
语言要点。好了，我们要看的词大多
have to do with underwear, describing underwear. Right. And the first one is granny panties.
和内衣有关，描述内衣。对。第一个是granny panties。
Granny panties. Granny panties. This isn't like a real, real word, right? It's not something
Granny panties。Granny panties。这不是一个真正的词，对吧？这不是你
you'll find in a dictionary. No, it's a slang word and we use it to describe really big,
会在字典里找到的词。不，这是一个俚语，用来形容很大、
ugly underwear like your grandmother would wear. All right, so they're not like the sexy
难看的内衣，就像你奶奶会穿的那种。好了，所以它们不是那种性感的
little underwear. It's more like long and it's not very appealing. Just picture what
小内衣。更像是长的，不太吸引人。想象一下
your grandmother would wear. No. All right, so granny panties. So obviously this guy doesn't
你奶奶会穿什么。不。好了，所以granny panties。显然这个男人不想
want to be buying any of those, but the saleswoman suggests that he try some sleepwear. Sleepwear.
买那些，但女售货员建议他试试睡衣。Sleepwear。
Sleepwear. Okay, so sleepwear. Obviously, clothes you wear when you're sleeping. Now,
Sleepwear。好，sleepwear。显然，是你睡觉时穿的衣服。现在，
this is really interesting because men aren't really that complicated when it comes to sleeping.
这很有趣，因为男人在睡觉方面没那么复杂。
Just throw on a t-shirt and that's it. Well, obviously for women, there are more options
随便穿件T恤就行了。嗯，显然对女人来说，有更多选择
and more different things you can choose from. Okay. So it's a whole separate category for
和更多不同的东西可以选。好。所以对女人来说这是一个单独的类别。
women. I know. Even when you're sleeping, you must wear something nice. Yes. One type
我知道。即使睡觉时，你也得穿好看的衣服。是的。一种
of sleepwear is silky nighties. Nighties. Nighties. N-I-G-H-T-I-E-S. Okay, so a nightie.
睡衣是丝质睡裙。Nighties。Nighties。N-I-G-H-T-I-E-S。好，nightie。
It's basically a dress that you wear when you sleep. Okay. Now, the pronunciation is
基本上就是你睡觉时穿的连衣裙。好。现在，发音
interesting because the first five letters are night. Right. Right, but you don't say
很有趣，因为前五个字母是night。对。对，但你不说
night. You don't say nighty. You say nighty. Yeah, you make the T a D. Nighty. Now, she
nighty。你说nighty。是啊，你把T发成D。Nighty。现在，她
offered him some silky nighties. Right. So, silky. Obviously, we know silk is a soft,
给他推荐了一些丝质睡裙。对。所以，silky。显然，我们知道丝绸是一种柔软、
shiny fabric, right? Right. So when something is silky, it's either made from silk or it's
有光泽的面料，对吧？对。所以当某物是silky时，要么是丝绸做的，要么是
soft and shiny. Okay, so some silky nighties. Very soft, shiny nighties. Exactly. Okay.
柔软有光泽的。好，一些丝质睡裙。非常柔软、有光泽的睡裙。没错。好。
What about our next word? Well, the sales girl offers different styles of undies. Undies.
下一个词呢？嗯，女售货员推荐了不同风格的内裤。Undies。
Undies. Undies. So, undies is an interesting word. It's basically short for underwear.
Undies。Undies。所以，undies是一个有趣的词。它基本上是underwear的简称。
Underwear. Okay. So, you can just call underwear undies. Yes, but I think you mostly use this
Underwear。好。所以你可以直接叫内衣undies。是的，但我觉得你大多
when you're talking about women's underwear. Oh, really? I mean, I don't know if I would
在谈论女式内衣时用这个词。哦，真的吗？我的意思是，我不知道我是否
say undies when I'm talking about men's underwear. No, I don't think so. Maybe children's underwear.
会在谈论男式内衣时说undies。不，我不这么认为。也许儿童内衣。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. For children. For children, right? Yep. Okay. All right, so we saw some
是啊，是啊，是啊。给儿童的。给儿童的，对吧？是的。好。好了，我们看到了一些
of the different types of clothing, but now let's take a look at this interesting adjective.
不同类型的衣服，但现在我们来看看这个有趣的形容词。
Mortifying. Mortifying. This is mortifying. Mortifying. Okay, so when something is mortifying.
Mortifying。Mortifying。这太丢人了。Mortifying。好，当某事是mortifying时。
Well, I think we've got some examples to show you what that is like. Example one. And then
嗯，我觉得我们有一些例子可以展示这是什么感觉。例子一。然后
I fell in front of everyone. It was mortifying. Example two. I was completely mortified when
我在大家面前摔倒了。太丢人了。例子二。当我意识到我做了什么时，我完全
I realized what I had done. Example three. It must have been mortifying for her when
感到丢脸。例子三。当她意识到她的内衣露出来时，那一定很丢人。
she realized that her underwear was showing. So, basically, it's very embarrassing. Super
所以，基本上就是非常尴尬。超级
embarrassing. You want to die almost. Yep. Okay. Which is interesting. I mean, mort.
尴尬。你几乎想死。是的。好。这很有趣。我的意思是，mort。
Right from death, right? Yeah, French. Yeah, interesting. All right. Well, etymology here
来自死亡，对吧？是啊，法语。是啊，有趣。好了。嗯，这里是EnglishPod的词源学。
at EnglishPod. All right, so some interesting... Okay, so we saw the different types of underwear.
好了，一些有趣的……好，我们看到了不同类型的内衣。
We saw this really great word for when you're really embarrassed. So, now let's take a look
我们看到了这个很棒的词，用来形容你非常尴尬的时候。所以，现在我们来看看
at some of the phrases that you would use when you're really embarrassed in Fluency
一些当你很尴尬时会用的短语，在流利度
Builder. Fluency Builder. All right, well, we have two phrases to look at here. The first
构建中。流利度构建。好了，我们要看两个短语。第一个
one. Get the hell out of here. Get the hell out of here. Get the hell out of here. Okay,
是Get the hell out of here。Get the hell out of here。Get the hell out of here。好，
so if I say, I want to get the hell out of here. You want to leave this place really
如果我说，我想get the hell out of here。你想非常快地离开这个地方。
quickly. Really quickly. Yes. I want to leave. Right now. Now, when you're using this phrase
非常快。是的。我想离开。现在。当你用这个短语
or this sentence, get the hell out of here. Is it really polite? No, of course not. It's
或这个句子时，get the hell out of here。它很有礼貌吗？不，当然不。它
impolite. Okay, so it's really negative. Very negative and informal, right? Yeah. So, you
是不礼貌的。好，所以它很负面。非常负面且非正式，对吧？是啊。所以，你
would use this maybe with your friends or like in this case, think it to yourself. Yes,
可能和朋友用，或者像这种情况，在心里想。是的，
but it's not a good idea to use with your boss or your mother. Right. Yeah. Okay. I
但最好不要对老板或妈妈用。对。是啊。好。我
guess sometimes depending on the tone you use, how you say it, you can sound really
猜有时取决于你用的语气，你怎么说，你可以听起来很
angry, right? Definitely. Right. Okay. All right. Well, let's listen to some examples.
生气，对吧？当然。对。好。好了，我们来听一些例子。
Example one. This place is scary. Let's get the hell out of here. Example two. What are
例子一。这个地方很吓人。我们赶紧离开这里。例子二。你在
you doing in my house? Get the hell out of here. Example three. We're at a friend's party
我家里干什么？滚出去。例子三。我们在一个朋友的派对上，
and all of a sudden her parents arrived. We got the hell out of there as quickly as possible.
突然她父母来了。我们尽快离开了那里。
All right. So, get the hell out of here. Get the hell out of here. Now, let's take a look
好了。所以，get the hell out of here。Get the hell out of here。现在，我们来看看
at our last phrase for a fluency builder. Get this over with. Get this over with. I
流利度构建的最后一个短语。Get this over with。Get this over with。我
want to get this over with. So, you want to finish it really quickly. But you want to
想get this over with。所以你想很快完成它。但你想
finish it because you're not really enjoying it, right? Exactly. This is something that
完成它是因为你并不真的享受它，对吧？没错。这是
you use when the situation is negative. Is negative. Okay. Yeah. Okay. So, I just want
你在情况负面时用的。是负面的。好。是啊。好。所以，我只想
to get this over with. Yeah. I want to get this test over with. I want to get this day
赶紧结束这件事。是啊。我想赶紧考完试。我想赶紧过完这一天。
over with. I want to get this... Maybe if you're on a bad date, I want to get this date
我想赶紧……也许如果你在糟糕的约会中，我想赶紧结束这次约会。
over with. Yes, exactly. All right. Well, interesting phrases and I think it would help
是的，没错。好了。有趣的短语，我觉得
us to hear them once more in context in the dialogue.
在对话中再听一遍会更有帮助。
This sucks. I hate buying lingerie. Okay, just find something and get out of here. All
真烦。我讨厌买内衣。好，随便找点东西然后离开这里。好，
right, these are fine. Oh, no. Don't come over here. Don't come over here. You look
这些还行。哦，不。别过来。别过来。你看起来
a little lost. Can I help you? I'm just having a look around. It's my girlfriend's birthday
有点迷茫。需要帮忙吗？我只是随便看看。明天是我女朋友的生日。
tomorrow. I'm trying to find her something. Well, you can't give her granny panties. Have
我想给她找点东西。嗯，你不能给她买老奶奶内裤。你有没有
you thought about getting her some sleepwear? We've got these lovely silky nighties or how
想过给她买点睡衣？我们有这些可爱的丝质睡裙，或者
about some nice panties in a bra set? Look, here's a nice satin push-up bra and you can
来点漂亮的内裤和文胸套装怎么样？看，这是个不错的缎面聚拢文胸，你可以
choose a few different styles of undies to go with it. Sure, that's fine. This is so
选几种不同风格的内裤来搭配。好的，可以。这太
awkward. What ones do I pick? What size is she? Well, do you want a thong? Some bikini
尴尬了。我选哪些？她穿什么尺码？嗯，你想要丁字裤吗？一些比基尼
briefs? Maybe this nice pair of lacy boy shorts? Just pick something and get the hell out of
内裤？也许这条漂亮的蕾丝平角短裤？随便挑一个然后赶紧离开
here. I'll go with these two. This is mortifying. I just want to get this over with and she
这里。我就选这两个。这太丢人了。我只想赶紧结束这件事，她
better thank me for this. Here you are, sir. I'm sure she'll enjoy them. Finally. I'm sorry,
最好感谢我。给您，先生。我相信她会喜欢的。终于好了。对不起，
sir. I'm going to have to take a look inside your bag.
先生。我得检查一下你的包。
All right. So I guess this situation is very common. Men either having to shop for this
好了。所以我猜这种情况很常见。男人要么必须为女朋友或妻子买这种
type of article for their girlfriend or wife because it's their birthday or sometimes we
东西，因为她们的生日，有时我们
get dragged into a store to buy this. So you're shopping with your girlfriend and she's going
会被拖进商店买这个。所以你和女朋友一起购物，她会
to make you go look at underwear with her. Yeah. I usually don't do that though. I'll
让你和她一起看内衣。是啊。但我通常不那样做。我会
just go to the next section and just look around. Look at tools. Look at TVs and Play
去下一个区随便看看。看工具。看电视和Play
Stations. But you know what? I have seen some men who go shopping with their girlfriends
Station。但你知道吗？我见过一些男人和女朋友或妻子一起购物，
or wives and actually enjoy buying underwear. See, that's the thing. I think it makes sense,
实际上很享受买内衣。看，这就是问题所在。我觉得这有道理，
but I don't know how comfortable you would actually be. I don't know why. I guess just
但我不确定你会有多自在。我不知道为什么。我猜只是
how it indicates sexuality and all this stuff. I could do it for maybe five or ten minutes,
因为它涉及性之类的东西。我可以做五到十分钟，
give my professional advice and then I'm out of there. All right. Well, maybe those guys
给出我的专业建议，然后我就走了。好了。嗯，也许那些
who look like they're enjoying themselves are just really talking in their heads, telling
看起来很享受的男人只是在心里说，
themselves how much they hate this. Exactly. Maybe they're just pretending or listening
告诉自己他们有多讨厌这个。没错。也许他们只是在假装，或者在听
to their iPod. Well, tell us, well, guys, I know we've got a lot of male listeners.
他们的iPod。嗯，告诉我们，嗯，各位，我知道我们有很多男性听众。
Tell us what you think. Are you embarrassed by women's underwear? Right. Or women, why
告诉我们你的想法。你对女式内衣感到尴尬吗？对。或者女性，为什么
aren't you embarrassed when you buy men's underwear for your boyfriend or husband? I
当你为男朋友或丈夫买男式内衣时不感到尴尬？我
think there's a lot to talk about here. So, come to our website at EnglishPod.com. Right.
觉得这里有很多可以讨论的。所以，来我们的网站EnglishPod.com。对。
Leave your questions and comments and of course, tell us what you think about this topic. Well,
留下你的问题和评论，当然，告诉我们你对这个话题的看法。好了，
thanks for downloading this lesson and until next time, goodbye.
感谢下载这节课，下次再见，再见。